ACWA Rochester Joint Board Records 5273
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACWA Rochester Joint Board Records
1920-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACWA Rochester Joint Board
5273
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Broadsides (notices), minutes (administrative records).
Meeting minutes, 1919-1932; Broadsides, 1966
8214554
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 13, 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The Joint Board of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America coordinated union activities in the Rochester, N.Y. area.
In 1915, the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA) embarked on a large-scale organizing drive in Rochester, N.Y. After four years of extensive organizing, the union succeeded in forcing the Rochester Clothiers' Exchange (the main organization of employers) into adopting a 44-hour workweek. By 1929, the union had succeeded in unionizing over 12,000 of Rochester's clothing workers.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5273 mf: ACWA Rochester Joint Board Minutes of Meeting on Microfilm 5285 mf: ACWA Rochester Joint Board Scrapbooks on Microfilm 5416 mf: William M. Leiserson Decisions on Microfilm 5619: ACWA Records 5619: ACWA Records 5619/043 AV: ACWA Rochester Joint Board Audio-Visual Materials 5993 mf: ACWA Rochester Joint Board Minutes on Microfilm
Bakery Strike, Syracuse, N.Y., 1925; Clothing Workers' Strike, Buffalo, N.Y., 1919; Textile Workers' Strike, Passaic, N.J., 1926; Italian Americans -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Off Pressers' Strike, Rochester, N.Y., 1927; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1924; Racketeering -- United States; Sacco-Vanzetti Trial, Dedham, Mass., 1921; Sex discrimination in employment -- United States; Silk Workers' Strike, Paterson, N.J., 1924; Stein Block Sitdown Strike, Rochester, N.Y., 1927; Labor unions and communism -- United States; Labor unions and fascism -- Italy; Labor unions and foreign policy -- United States; United Mine Workers' Strike, United States, 1926; United Shoe Workers' Strike, United States, 1922; United Shoe Workers' Strike, United States, 1926; Women labor union members -- United States; Clothing workers -- New York (State); Clothing industry -- Economic aspects -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Grievance procedures -- Clothing industry -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Strikes and lockouts -- Clothing industry -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Strikes and lockouts -- Men's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Rochester -- Factionalism; Labor unions -- Jurisdictional disputes -- New York (State) -- Rochester; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- Rochester -- Social activity; Labor unions -- United States -- Social action; Wages -- Clothing industry -- New York (State) -- Rochester; United States -- Emigration and immigration; Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley; Gold, Ben; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion),1895-1953; Longuet, Jean; Matteotti, Giacomo, 1885-1924; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942; Sacco, Nicola, 1891-1927; Schlossberg, Joseph, 1875-1971; Vanzetti, Bartolomeo, 1888-1927; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Rochester Joint Board; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; American Civil Liberties Union; Brookwood Labor College (Katonah, N.Y.); Colorado Fuel and Iron Company; Farmer-Labor Party; Furriers' Union of the United States of America and Canada; Hebrew Sheltering of Immigrant Aid Society of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Italian Chamber of Labor; Jewish Charitable Institute; National Labor Alliance for Trade Relations with and Recognition of Russia; Russian American Industrial Cooperation Committee; Socialist Party (U.S.); Trade Union Educational League (U.S.); United Brotherhood of Cloak Makers of New York; United Shoe Workers of America
8214554
- Minutes, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Minutes, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Minutes, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Minutes, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Union Election Material, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)